Tyson Bradford

London, England, United Kingdom

Email: tys.bradford@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tyson-bradford-04063b37

Summary

Experienced Engineering Manager and Tech Leader with a strong background in mobile application development and team leadership. Open to opportunities that are centred around innovation, ambitious products that aim to provide huge value, and working alongside passionate people. Currently fascinated and very optimistic around generative AI technologies.

Professional Experience

ZAVA

Engineering Manager (Mar 2022 - Present)

- Launched and grew a brand new telemedicine application across iOS and Android platforms.
- Established the team as a top digital primary care provider.
- Released multiple innovative and first-to-market digital health experiences for patients.

Lead Engineer (Mar 2020 - Mar 2022)

Rated People

Software Development Manager (Mobile) (Feb 2019 - Mar 2020)

- Managed a portfolio of four native mobile applications as part of a two-sided platform.
- Led the team to create reliable and market-leading mobile experiences for customers.
- Hands-on coding and development.

Lead iOS Developer (Feb 2018 - Mar 2020)

Blue Tropical Pty Ltd

Founder, Director, Engineer (May 2013 - Jan 2019)

- Established a mobile development shop to deliver multiple mobile projects.
- Managed development, project management, product strategy, and business operations.

Gigster

Freelance Mobile App Developer (2015 - 2017)

• Delivered world-class mobile apps to clients around the globe.

Klyp

Mobile Lead (Feb 2014 - Aug 2015)

- Native iOS and Android app development.
- Pioneered iBeacon solutions.
- Testing, QA, and deployment to app stores.
- Team management and product development focused on user experience.

Sedgman Pty Limited

Software & Controls Engineer (Feb 2011 - Jul 2012)

Education

The University of Queensland

• Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Mechatronics (2006 - 2010)

Lund University

• Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Controls Engineering, Commerce (2009 - 2009)

Brisbane Grammar School

Skills

- Cross-functional Team Leadership
- Project Delivery
- Team Management
- Generative AI
- iOS Development
- Product Development
- Engineering Management
- Product Design
- Programming
- Automation